Marien Sakakibara

São Paulo, BR • +55 (11) 986915413 • mariensakakibara@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mariensakakibara • mariensakakibara.notion.site

Marketing and Data Analyst

+5 years of experience in account, campaign and project management for agencies, SMBs and Global players, focusing on digital marketing strategies and data growth analysis for branding and performance in tech, gaming and CPG markets for both the web and mobile.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Client Solutions Manager · Full-time Aleph Group

São Paulo, BR 06/2022 - 06/2024

- Self-serve: Snapchat, Electronic Arts, Activision Blizzard, Roblox
- Project Management: manage the entire lifecycle of multiple ad campaigns; implement quality control processes.
- Campaign Management: plan, set up, optimize, and report on ad campaigns for global and local brands; conduct research and analysis to improve performance and decision-making; conduct A/B testing and manage Conversion/Brand Lift.
- Client Management: act as the point of contact with clients, agencies, and partners for support, recommendations, and presentations related to Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).
- Cross-functional Collaboration: provide support to the Sales team with research and strategies; communicate with the Creative team to develop compelling materials aligned with campaign objectives; offer operational support for other teams.

Account Manager · Full-time

São Paulo, BR

07/2021 - 05/2022

Self-Serve: Pinterest

Accenture

- Account Management: monitor and track the performance of multiple accounts; determine short and longrange sales revenue plans.
- Campaign Management: optimize ad campaigns for Brazilian SMBs to improve performance.
- Client Management: act as the point of contact with clients for support and recommendations related to Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).
- Project Management: plan, develop, and present technical training for the Pinterest team and clients; implement quality control processes.

Public Relations Intern

Speyside 02/2021 - 06/2021

- · Clients: Stripe, ACI Worldwide, Subway, GSK
- Media Monitoring: perform press clipping and reporting; identify opportunities for client coverage in media outlets.
- Media Relations: build and maintain relationships with the press and agencies; respond to media requests and shadow interviews.
- Content Creation: write and report on events, workshops, and briefings for journalists and stakeholders.
- Administrative Support: schedule meetings, manage calendars, and handle correspondence with other internal teams.

Public Relations Intern

BCW Brasil 10/2020 - 02/2021

- · Client: Nespresso
- Media Monitoring: perform press clipping and generate quantitative reports; identify opportunities for client coverage in media outlets.
- Research and Analysis: analyze partnership proposals and potential influencers for future contracts.
- Media Relations: follow up with the press and influencers.
- Content Creation: write and report on press releases and social media content.
- Administrative Support: schedule meetings, manage calendars, and handle correspondence with other internal teams.

Customer Success

CX Contact 07/2019 - 12/2019

- Self-serve: Dufry
- Client Management: act as the point of contact with worldwide customers for support and cross-selling opportunities.
- Project Management: assist the Sales team in creating strategic approaches for sales strategies.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Public Relations

Faculdade Cásper Líbero SP, Brazil

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Analyst 06/2024

Google

SKILLS

Language: Native in Portuguese, Proficient in English

AdTech: Google Ads, Linkedin Ads, Meta Ads, Pinterest Ads, Programmatic, Snapchat Ads, TikTok Ads

CRM tools: Hubspot, Salesforce

Data tools: Excel, Looker Studio, Tableau

Presentation: Google Suite, iWork, Microsoft office